Andrew Ascone

Software Developer

Contact Information

• Phone: (848) 218-3402

• Email: andrew.ascone@gmail.com

GitHub: AndrewAsconeLinkedIn: Andrew-Ascone

Summary

Dedicated, methodical Software Developer seeking new career challenges by integrating a B.S. in Communications and 7+ years of customer service experience. Able to anticipate client needs and produce viable solutions to problems with key skills including effective communication, project management, application of technology-based solutions, and data analytics.

Technical Skills

Java • SQL • Spring Boot • Postman • MySQL • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • TypeScript • Git

Experience

ReUnion Rx

Atlantic Highlands, NJ

Pharmaceutical Delivery Driver | Dec 2017 - Present

• Deliver vital pharmaceutical products to nursing homes and mental health facilities with 100% accuracy achieved by verifying stocks of medications and maintaining computer inventory records.

Zip Code Wilmington

Wilmington, DE

Software Developer | Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

Admitted in and completed Zip Code Wilmington's software development program which accepts less than 10% of applicants; completed over 1000 hours of software development projects in immersive, full-stack training using Agile and Scrum methodologies and test-driven development; gained experience with multiple object-oriented programming languages and frameworks.

Monmouth Telecom

Red Bank, NJ

Network Operations Tech | May 2022 - Oct 2022

• Coordinated with a team of 4 troubleshooting and resolving technical issues related to routing services and telephone equipment; provided excellent customer service to an average of 8 clients per day.

Shamrock Stagecoach

Keansburg, NJ

Bus Driver | *Feb* 2015 - *May* 2022

• Transported 10-12 students on 3 different routes daily in a safe manner, keeping within 3 minutes of estimated arrival time.

Projects

- Group Project: Dialogue Alley Collaboratively worked on a team of 3 to develop an online forum capable of posting messages, tagging other users, uploading images, and filtering content by user or by hashtag. Personally contributed to the front-end design using React and creating the REST API with Spring Boot. Developed using Java, Spring Boot, React, and MySQL
- *Personal Project*: Demo CRUD Server Developed and deployed a demo server for managing entries in an H2 database. Developed using Java, Spring Boot, JQuery, and H2. Live demo deployed using render.com.

Certifications

JPMorgan Chase & Co. Software Engineering Lite virtual experience program on Forage | December 2023

- Completed a simulation focused on the process of completing an engineering ticket for a system in the creditcard rewards department of JPMorgan Chase & Co.
- Created a new class to get an existing system up and running
- Wrote a test suite for the class added

Education

Champlain College

Burlington, VT

B.S. in Communication | *May 2013*